hm-treasury.gov.uk 2013-04-24

# Privacy statement and Cookies - HM Treasury

##  What is a Cookie? 

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. These pieces of information are used to make the website work or improve services for you through, for example: 

  * enabling a service to recognise your device so you don't have to give the same information several times during one task; 
  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested; 
  * measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast. 

We sometimes embed photo and video content from websites such as YouTube and Flickr. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Flickr, you may be presented with cookies from these websites.  We do not control the dissemination of these cookies.  You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these. 

##  How government websites use Cookies 

##  Can I control or delete Cookies? 

All recent versions of popular browsers (such as Internet Explorer, Google Chrome or Mozilla Firefox) allow you to control cookies.  Typically, you can set your browser to accept or reject all, or certain cookies.  You might, for example, be happy to accept a cookie that allows you to log in to a website, but prefer to reject any which are used to build a profile of your internet usage.  You should also be able to set your browser to prompt you each time a cookie is offered. 

Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of this website. 

For more detailed instructions on how to control or delete cookies on different browsers, please visit <http://www.aboutcookies.org/>

##  List of the main HM Treasury Cookies 

This is a list of the main cookies set by the HM Treasury website, and what each is used for. 

Cookie Name 

  * ASP.net_Sessionid 

Purpose 

  * The ASP.NET session state is a technology that lets you store server-side, user-specific data. Web applications can use this data to process user requests. 

##  Third Party Cookies 

HM Treasury uses several suppliers who also set cookies on the HM Treasury website in order to deliver the services they are providing. If you would like more information about the cookies used by these suppliers, as well as information on how to opt-out, please see their individual privacy policies listed below. 

  * Google Analytics: This is a web analytics service provided by Google.  HM Treasury uses this service to measure how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast; 
    * [Google’s Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy); 

  * Issuu: HM Treasury uses Issuu to publish easy-to-read versions of PDF documents. 

  * Webtrends: This is a web analytics service provided by Webtrends.  HM Treasury uses this service to measure how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast. 

  * AddToAny (Lockerz): HM Treasury uses AddToAny to enable you to share our pages and content with social media sites such as Facebook, Google+ and Twitter. AddToAny uses several cookies to generate statistics on social media sharing. 

We sometimes embed photos and video content from websites such as YouTube and Flickr. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Flickr, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. We do not control the dissemination of these cookies.  You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these. 

###  Third party Cookies used by the HM Treasury website 

Used by  |  File name  |  Expires  |  Purpose  |  Further information   
---|---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics  |   _utma  |  2 years from set/update  |  These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  |  [An overview of privacy at Google](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)  
  |   _utmb  |  30 minutes from set/update  |  [Use of cookies by Google Analytics](http://code.google.com/apis/analytics/docs/concepts/gaConceptsCookies.html)  
  |   _utmc  |  On closing browser  |     
  |   _utmz  |  6 months from set/update  |     
  |   _utmv  |  2 years from set/update  |     
AddToAny (Lockerz)  |   _utma  |  2 years from set/update  |  These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where vistors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  |  [AddToAny Privacy Policy and opt-out instructions](http://share.lockerz.com/privacy)  
  |   _utmb  |  30 minutes from set/update  |     
  |   _utmc  |  On closing browser  |     
  |   _utmz  |  6 months from set/update  |     
  |   _utmv  |  2 years from set/update  |     
  |   uvc  |  1 hour from set/update  |   Bookmarking Cookie   
Webtrends  |   WT_FPC  |  10 years from set/update  |  This is a web analytics service provided by Webtrends.  HM Treasury uses this service to measure how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast.  |  [Webtrends Privacy Policy](http://webtrends.com/privacy-policy/)

Issuu  |   _utma  |  2 years from set/update  |  These cookies are used by Issuu to collect information on how many visitors are using the easy-to-read versions of documents on the HM Treasury site.  |  [Issuu’s Privacy Policy](http://issuu.com/about/privacy)  
  |   _utmb  |  30 minutes from set/update  |     
  |   _utmc  |  On closing browser  |     
  |   _qca  |  5 years from set/update  |     

##  Social Media sharing tools 

We would like to draw your attention to the fact that this website now carries embedded ‘share’ buttons to enable users of the site to easily share articles with their friends through a number of popular social networks. These sites may set a cookie when you are also logged in to their service. HM Treasury does not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third party website for more information about these. 

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, your computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally.  

##  Website usage information 

This website does not store or capture personal information, but merely logs the users Internet Protocol (IP) address*. Our log files for the site do not contain any personal information or information about other sites you have visited. 

Other web sites linked from this site do not necessarily follow the same policies. Further information on your rights under the Data Protection Act 1998 can be found on the [Information Commissioner's Website](http://www.dataprotection.gov.uk/). 

If you have any queries about this privacy statement, you can contact us at [editor@hm-treasury.gov.uk](mailto:editor@hm-treasury.gov.uk). 

Back to top
